<resources>
    <string name="app_name">planto</string>
    <string name="desc">836 Battle monument Gray stone obelisk on a rectangular pedestal of the same stone. Behind the monument is a wooden bridge across a river. The Minute Man can be seen in the far background beyond the bridge. The 1836 obelisk with The Minute Man in the background on the other side of the Concord River In 1825, the Bunker Hill Monument Association donated $500 (equivalent to $11,437 in 2020) to Concord to build a monument to the Battle of Concord.[18] The original plan was to place the monument \"near the town pump\" in Concord.[19] Due to disagreements within the town, nothing was done with the money until Ezra Ripley donated land for the monument near the Old North Bridge in 1835. After the donation, the town had Solomon Willard design a simple 25-foot-tall (7.6-meter) granite obelisk to commemorate the 60th anniversary of the Battle of Concord.[19] The \"Concord Hymn\" was written by transcendentalist writer Ralph Waldo Emerson for the dedication of the monument in 1836.[20] At the ceremony, it was sung to the tune of \"Old Hundred\".[21]  To the dislike of Emerson, the obelisk stands on the bank of the river where the British stood during battle.[22] The Minute Man was created for the centennial celebration of the battle in 1875. Unlike the earlier monument, it was to be placed on the bank where the Massachusetts militia stood.[22]  Creation and unveiling The monument committee for The Minute Man—which consisted of George M. Brooks, John B. More, John S. Keyes, and Emerson—only considered Daniel Chester French because he was from Concord and his father, Henry F. French, was a prominent local lawyer and former judge.[23] The statue was French\'s first full-size work; previously French had produced a bust of his father and one additional statue.[24] In 1871, a year before he was formally commissioned, the committee chairman asked French to start working on the statue.[23] Throughout the year, French sketched possible poses for the statue. That summer, he created a small clay \"related figure\" that was rejected by the committee.[23][25] It is unknown what that statue looked like and it was not saved.[25]  French researched The Minute Man by studying powder horns and buttons from the era.[26] According to Harold Holzer, because French was a handsome man, \"there would be a line of young women outside his studio ready to show him their alleged Colonial artifacts\" to help him with his research.[24] After a months-long search, a plow from the correct era was located to model for the statue.[27] In 1873, his second clay model of the statue was accepted by the statue committee.[28] The same year, the medium of the statue was changed from stone to bronze.[25] The miniature version of the statue won a local art competition in September 1873, but the pose of the figure was deemed \"awkwardly stiff\" by critics.[29] The pose of The Minute Man was made more natural in the enlargement process by working with models. By September 1874, the statue was completed and a plaster version of the clay statue was sent to Ames Manufacturing Works in Chicopee, Massachusetts.[30] Because the town did not have the money to cast the statue in bronze, through a bill introduced by Ebenezer R. Hoar, the United States Congress appropriated ten Civil War-era cannons[note 2] to the project.[31][32] The statue was cast with the metal from guns.[25]  The statue was unveiled on April 19, 1875, during the centennial celebration of the Battle of Concord, in a ceremony attended by President Ulysses S. Grant and Ralph Waldo Emerson.[33][34] French, however, left for Italy to further study sculpture in 1874 and was not in attendance. Holzer suggests that French avoided the celebration \"in case the statue was panned\" by contemporary critics.[35] French\'s fears were unfounded and the statue was positively received by art critics and the public.[35]  The Concord Minute Man of 1775 French was commissioned by the town of Concord in 1889 to rework The Minute Man for the Yorktown-class gunboat USS Concord.[25] The new statue, paid for by Congress, was titled The Concord Minute Man of 1775.[note 3] The reworked statue cleaned up some imperfections in the face of the original statue and incorporated elements of Beaux-Arts.[25] French made the movement of the new statue more fluid and natural.[36] It was completed in 1890 and installed on the gunboat in 1891.[25] A copy of the statue was also carried by the Omaha-class cruiser USS Concord in the 1940s.[37]  Composition Statue Greened bronze statue of a young colonial man. He holds a rifle, and his coat is on a plow beside him. Closeup of The Minute Man without its pedestal The statue is 7 feet (2.1 meters) tall and depicts a minuteman at the Battle of Concord. It is, perhaps, a portrait of Isaac Davis,[note 4] an officer who died in the battle.[38] The farmer-turned-soldier is shown trading his plow for a musket[note 5] and stepping away from his private life toward the impending battle.[25] The sleeves of his coat and shirt are rolled up; the minuteman\'s overcoat is draped over the plow.[39] A powder horn, mistakenly, sits on the man\'s back instead of on his hip where it can be used.[39] His face is alert while his eyes are transfixed on the battle into which he is ready to march.[40] On his head sits a wide-brimmed hat that has been pinned on the right side.[27]  The pose of the soldier has been compared to the pose of the Apollo Belvedere.[41] Nineteenth- and twentieth-century art critics, such as Lorado Taft and H. C. Howard, have suggested that the pose was directly copied from the Roman sculpture.[41][42] Howard in particular trivializes the sculpture as \"little more than an Americanized rendition of the Apollo Belvedere\".[42] Modern scholarship, working with French\'s journals, disagrees that the pose is a copy while acknowledging that French used a variety of plaster casts of classical sculptures, including the Apollo Belvedere, as inspiration when creating The Minute Man.[43]</string>
    <string name="todo">TODO</string>
    <string name="plant_detail">No green thumb required to keep our artificial watermelon peperomia plant looking lively and lush anywhere you place it.</string>
    <string name="thatVeryPlantDetail">Just Scan and the \nAI will know exactly</string>
</resources>